RUBEN A. SANCHEZ



EDUCATION			
2015 2015	B.A. Linguistics B.S. Cognitive Science	University of California, Santa Cruz University of California, Santa Cruz	
PUBLICATION			
2019	Zyzik, E.C., & Sanchez , R.A. (2019). Beyond accurate on two kinds of acceptability judgment tasks. <i>Applied</i> http://doi.org/10.1017/S0142716418000760		
AWARDS			
2021 2015 2012 to 2014	Macquarie Group Scholarship UCSC Scholarship Undergraduate Dean's Award		
RESEARCH	SEARCH EXPERIENCE		
2017 to 2018	Data Analyst - Bilingualism Research Lab Responsible for conducting data pre-processing, codin analysis, inferential analysis, data visualizations, and		
2016	Annotator - Natural Language & Dialogue Systems Annotated social media content for computational monarrative summarizations.	University of California, Santa Cruz odeling via language entrainment and	
2013 to 2014	Research Assistant - Cognitive Science Department Coded acoustic data with Praat and video data with study.	University of California, Santa Cruz After Effects for a linguistic phonetic	
2012	Research Assistant - Linguistics Department Developed, implemented, and completed a phonologic stimuli, scheduled and ran participants, as well as and	• • • • • •	
TEACHING EXPERIENCE			
2020	Academic Success Mentor Served as advisor for student at risk of loosing resider - Guided student through studying best practices Developed a strategy plan for completing assignme - Advised on stress coping mechanisms and directed - Student successfully completed the quarter and gra-	nts. to resources.	
2018 to 2019	Private Tutor		

Tutored college students in mathematics.

LEADERSHIP & SERVICE

2018 to 2019 Volunteer - English composition tutor for international students.

2013 to 2014 Community Liaison Officer - Undergraduate Research Science Association

2012 Founder & President - Spanish Languages & Spanish Cultures Club

2011 Co-founder - Volunteer based community outreach writing tutoring service.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Expertise Cognitive research, neurolinguistics, phonetic psycholinguistics, data visualization,

web development, illustration, and 2D animation.

Research Interested in investigating the neural circuitry responsible for the assignment of semantic

Interests coding onto phonetic units perceived as linguistically relevant.

Also interested in multimodal communicative strategies for human computer interaction.

Programming Python, R, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GIT, CLI, bash, LATEX, markdown

Research E-Prime, SuperLab, Praat, Audacity, ELAN, SPSS, Mendeley, Zotero

Design Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Figma, Invision, Blender

Leadership Project Management, Team Building, Issue Resolution

Languages English, Italian, Spanish, learning Japanese

CURRENT PROJECTS

2021 Web Based Interactive 3D Brain Model

Teaching myself advanced 3D modeling methods for developing an interactive model of the human brain which displays areas currently known to be pertinent to the perception and production of sounds relevant to language.

- Completed design of graphical user interface.
- Completed engineering of information architecture.
- Completed development of shell infrastructure.
- Conducting formal literature review for content incorporation.

2 of 2 October 2021